A Guide to the University of Connecticut 1979.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series VI: Research Materials on Ethnic Groups, undated, 1897-1980
  - Blacks
    - Robinson, Elizabeth, A., "The Black Child in White America", 1975 (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - Tumin, Melvin M., Race and Intelligence, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 256)
  - Cameroun
    - Tembi, Roy, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 257)
  - Canadian-French
    - Beaulieu, Rose, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - Mrs. Johns", Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 259)
  - Cape Verdean
    - Tchuda; newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 260)
  - Carpatho-Ruthenians
    - Magocsi, Paul R., Carpatho-Ruthenians in North America; bibliography, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 261)
  - Chicanos
    - Para La Gente; newspaper, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 262)
  - Chilean
    - Alvarado, Luis, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 263)
  - Chinese
    - Chinese in CT; newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Chung Hwa School of San Diego, Inc., 1975 (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - "China Without Mao," Atlas, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Chinese in general; newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Chen, Kuan-Yu, "How China Conceptualizes its Future Through Education", 1972 (Box 9, Folder 268)
  - Chinese (Taiwanese)
    - "Cultural Relationships with Taiwan," Gist, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 269)
  - Cubans
    - Garcia, Luis, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 270)
  - Czechoslovakians
    - Boratko, John, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9:271)
  - Boratko, John, Oral history summary
    - The Egyptian American Association, Inc., undated (Box 9, Folder 272)
  - English
    - Coleman, Gerard, Oral history summary, undated (Box 9, Folder 273)
    - Erickson, Charlotte, English in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 274)
    - Posner, Tony, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 275)
  - Estonians
    - Maron, Vera, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 276)
  - French
    - Colman, Rosalie, "An Historical Analysis of the French/English Bilingual Education Programs Conducted in CT by the Daughters of the Holy Spirit", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 277-282)
    - Kihn, Phyllis, "The Value Family in CT", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Low, Betty-Bright, French in North America; bibliography, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 284)
  - Germans
    - Deman, Sigrun, Oral history transcript, undated (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - "Mr. Hoffer", Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 286)
    - Klopstein, Margaret, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 287)
    - Sarges, Heike, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 288)
    - Steele, Elizabeth and William Hebebrand, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 289)
    - Stein, Anne Marie, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 290)
    - Berquist, James M., Germans in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 291)
    - The German Tribune; newspaper, 1975 February (Box 9, Folder 292)
  - Greeks
    - Greek Cookbook, St. George Greek Orthodox Church, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Guiliotos, Mrs. George, "New Haven's Greek Orthodox Community", 1970 (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - Greeks in CT; newspaper clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 295)
    - "Georgia", Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - "Mary", Oral history transcript, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 297)
    - Psarellis, Steven, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 298)
    - Cutsumbis, Michael N., A Bibliographic Guide to Materials on Greeks in the United States, 1890-1968, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - Lagios, George A., "The Development of Greek American Education in the US: 1908-1973", 1976 (Box 9, Folder 300-310)
  - Guatemalans
    - "Reading Materials for use in Teaching About Various Culture", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 311)
  - Hungarians
    - Hungarians in the US and Canada; bibliography, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 312)
  - Indians
    - Dave, Sandeep, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 313)
    - Nanjundiah, Sadinand, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 314)
  - Irish
    - Colla, Sister Maria Beatrice, "St. Joseph College: Origin, Development and Growth," (Harford), 1964 (Box 10, Folder 315)
    - Cunningham, Sister Mary Joseph Benigna, "Historical Background of Parochial Education in the Diocese of Hartford", 1951 (Box 10, Folder 316)
    - Malcolm, (Sister) Mary Catherine Teresa, A century of Community Service by the Sisters of Mercy in the Diocese of Hartford, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 317)
    - Palmer, Mary C., "In Praise of Beauty: A Monograph on the Life of Reverend Andrew J. Kelly (Hartford), 1963 (Box 10, Folder 318)
    - Feinstein, Estelle F., The Early Irish in Stamford, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 319)
    - The Early Irish in Stamford, undated (Box 10, Folder 320)
    - "Connecticut Irishmen in the Revolution", undated (Box 10, Folder 321)
    - Irish in CT; biographies, undated (Box 10, Folder 322)
    - "Leaves from the Annals of the Sisters of Mercy" (CT), undated (Box 10, Folder 323)
    - Mckeon, Robert John, Oral history summary, undated (Box 10, Folder 324)
    - Schaal, Marguerite, Oral history transcript, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - The Advocate, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 326-334)
    - CNS Press releases, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 335-339)
    - Clark, Dennis J., Irish in North America; bibliography, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 340)
    - "Irish Contributions to the American Revolution", undated (Box 10, Folder 341)
    - Kelly, Timothy, J., family history, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 342)
    - Irish in general; newspaper clippings, undated (Box 10, Folder 343)
    - Kelly, Timothy J., "Sort of an Ethnography of Ireland", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 344)
  - Italians
    - Giuliana, Zia, "A Collection of Poetry" (Hartford), undated (Box 10, Folder 345)
    - Italians in Hartford; newspaper clippings, undated (Box 10, Folder 346)
    - Reviews of Armando Perretta's Take a Number (Hartford), undated (Box 10, Folder 347)
    - Dedication Programs; St. Michaels's Convent (New Haven), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 348)
    - Aresco, Maria, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 349)
    - Aresco, Maria, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 350)
    - The Connecticut Italian Bulletin, 1978 October (Box 10, Folder 351)
    - "Enrica", Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 352)
    - Guiel, Olga, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 353)
    - Guiel, Olga, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 354)
    - Longo, Salvatore, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 355)
    - Mayor, Thomas, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 356)
    - Perrioli, Carmel, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 357)
    - Scollo, Joseph, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 358)
    - La Voce (CT), 1974 October/December (Box 10, Folder 359)
    - Zacco, Mario, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 360)
    - American Italian Historical Association, undated (Box 10, Folder 361)
    - I-AM; Preview copy, undated (Box 10, Folder 362)
    - Immigration documents (passports, etc.), 1901, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 363)
    - Iorizzo, Juciano J., Italians in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 364)
    - Italian-American newsletters, 1974-1977 (Box 10, Folder 365)
    - Italians in the US; newspaper clippings, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 366)
    - "Italian-Americans of South Bend", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 367)
    - The National Italian-American News, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 368)
    - Vecoli, Rudolph J., " Color Me Red, White and Green", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 369)
    - Vecoli, Rudolph J., " Color Me Red, White and Green", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 370)
  - Japanese
    - Demeusy, Gerald J., "Japanese Woman Embrace American Ways" (Hartford), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 371)
    - Cloutier, Yuri, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 372)
    - Kitano, Harry H.L., Japanese in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 373)
  - Jews
    - Kraus, Sallie, "The Immigration of Eastern European Jews to Bridgeport, CT, 1890-1914", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 374)
    - Dedication of the new B'nai Israel (Bridgeport), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 375)
    - A guide to the greater Hartford Jewish Community, undated (Box 11, Folder 376)
    - Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford; family profile, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 377)
    - Jewish Leader, (New London), 1975 January (Box 11, Folder 378)
    - Jewish Leader, A Goodly Heritage: the Story of the Jewish Community in New London, 1860-1955, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 379)
    - Beth El; Fortieth anniversary, (Norwalk), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 380)
    - "A Tribute to Henry Meyers," (Norwalk), 1968 (Box 11, Folder 381)
    - Goldberg, Arthur, "The Jew in Norwich, CT", undated (Box 11, Folder 382)
    - The Stamford Jewish Voice, 1978 October (Box 11, Folder 383)
    - Klier, Sarah Katzman, "History of the Jewish Community of Waterbury", 1974 (Box 11, Folder 384)
    - Klier, Sarah Katzman, "History of the Jewish Community of Waterbury", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 385-388)
    - Feldman, Rebecca Hurwitz, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 389)
    - Freund, Simon, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 390)
    - Goldman, Samuel and Nettie, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 391)
    - Hoffenberg, Samuel, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 392)
    - Kantrowitz, Gussie, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 393)
    - Kantrowitz, Samuel, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 394)
    - Kopelman, Joseph, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 395)
    - Levy, Gertrude, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 396)
    - Pattison, David, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 397)
    - Perlstein, Alex, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 398)
    - Pessin, Celia, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 399)
    - Poses, Sadie, Oral history transcript, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 400)
    - Vershow, Mary Zinman, Oral history transc, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 401)
    - Schoem, David, "Cultural Dilemmas and Self-Deception in an Ethnic Minority School," (California), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 402)
    - "Haym Saloman, Life and Legend", undated (Box 11, Folder 403)
    - Jews in the United States, undated (Box 11, Folder 404)
    - Jews in the U.S.; newspaper clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 405)
    - May, Howard, "The Rise of Black Anti-Semitism", 1969 (Box 11, Folder 406)
    - Jews in general, undated (Box 11, Folder 407)
  - Koreans
    - Hahn, Byungchai, Co., "Academic Performance of Korean Children", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 408-409)
    - Hahn, Cora, "Relationship of Perceptions and Self- Evaluation among Korean-American Children, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 410)
  - Laotians
    - In Bridegport; newspaper clipping, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 411)
  - Latvians
    - "Ieva", Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 412)
    - In United States; newspaper clipping, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 413)
  - Lebanese
    - Lebanese, 1966, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 414)
  - Lithuanians
    - In general; newspaper clippings, 1976, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 415)
  - Mexicans
    - "Mexican-Americans of South Bend", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 416)
    - In United States; newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 417)
    - Navarro, Joseph P., Mexicans in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 418)
  - Moravians
    - Allen, Walser H., The Story of Early Bethlehem in Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 419)
    - Allen, Walser H., Who are the Moravians?, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 420)
    - Murphy, Patricia Shaubah The Moravian Mission to the African Slaves of the Danish West Indies 1732-1828, undated (Box 11, Folder 421)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Box 11, Folder 422)
  - Native Americans
    - Guillette, Mary E., American Indians in CT, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 423)
    - Artifacts, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 424)
    - Review of book, Native Harvests by Barrie Kavasch, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 425)
  - Norwegians
    - Haugen, Einar, The Norwegians in America, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 426)
    - Smemo, Kenneth, Norwegians in North America; bibliography, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 427)
    - In general; newspaper clippings, photos of traditional costume, undated (Box 11, Folder 428)
  - Poles
    - The History of the Janik Sausage Co. (Enfield), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 429)
    - Historja Parafji Polskich w Djecezji Hatfordskiej, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 430)
    - Buczek, Daniel S., Immigrant Pastor (New Britain), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 431)
    - The Polish Full Gospel Church (New Britain), undated (Box 11, Folder 432)
    - WPA, Poles of New Britain, 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 433)
    - Holy Trinity Lutheran Church (Stafford Springs), undated (Box 11, Folder 434)
    - 75 Years Church and People (Stamford), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 435)
    - Golden Jubilee Program (Torrington), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 436)
    - "Frances," Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 437)
    - Koniar, Joseph M., Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 438)
    - Noga, Joseph, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 439)
    - Rosh, Anna, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 440)
    - Warkzala, Joseph, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 441)
    - In CT, newspaper clippings, 1975, 1978, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 442)
    - In CT; short biographies of Moe Drbowsky and Michael (Grninski?), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 443)
    - Polonia in Connecticut, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 444)
    - In United States; newspaper clippings, 1975, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 445)
    - Biography of Ted Knight (Tadeus Wladyslaw Konopka), undated (Box 12, Folder 446)
    - Chrobot, Leonard F., "Ethnic Awareness and Self-Identity", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 447)
    - Chorbot, Leonard F., "Who am I?", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 448)
    - The Copernicus Society, undated (Box 12, Folder 449)
    - Golab, Caroline,Poles in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 450)
    - The Kosciuszko Foundation (incl. newsletters), 1975 (Box 12, Folder 451)
    - Kusielewicz, Eugene, A Tribute to Stephen P. Mizw, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 452)
    - A Tribute to Stephen P. Mizw, Faith and Destiny, 1975 (Box 12:453, Folder 45)
    - "Magnificant," Felician Sisters, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 454)
    - Novak, Michael, ed., Growing up Slavic in America, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 455)
    - The Polish Review, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 456-457)
    - The Quarterly Review, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 458)
    - "Response", Felician Sisters Centennial in America, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 459)
    - Swastek, Joseph, "The Polish American Story", 1953 (Box 12, Folder 460)
    - "Tadeusz Kosciuszko" An address by Stephen P. Mizwa, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 461)
    - Waldo, Arthur L., First Poles in America, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 462)
    - Winowska, Maria, Go Repair My House, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 463)
    - Biuletyn, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 464)
    - "Historical Outline, 1943-1973" (Box 12, Folder 465)
  - Portuguese
    - In CT; Newspaper clippings, 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 466)
    - Rogers, Francis M., Portuguese in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 467)
  - Puerto Ricans
    - In Hartford, Newspaper clippings, 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 468-469)
    - Leach, John N., "Cultural Factors Affecting the Adjustment of Puerto Rican Children to Schooling in Hartford, CT", 1975 (Box 12, Folder 470)
    - Prewitt, Joseph O., "Cultural 'Bagaje' of Puerto Rican pupils," (Hartford), undated (Box 12, Folder 471)
    - Prewitt, Joseph O., "The Puerto Rican in Hartford", undated (Box 12, Folder 472)
    - In New Britain, St. Mary's, undated (Box 12, Folder 473)
    - In Willimantic, newspaper clipping, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 474)
    - "Maria", Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 475)
    - Villafane, Judith Maria Oxholm, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 476)
    - Quinones-Hernandez, Luis R., Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 477)
    - In CT; newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 478)
    - Governors Council on Spanish-Speaking Opportunities, Implementation 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 479)
    - Cordasco, Francesco, Puerto Ricans in North America; bibliography, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 480)
    - Maldonado, Rita M., "Why Puerto Ricans Migrated to the US in 1947-1973", 1976 (Box 12, Folder 481)
    - Prewitt, Joseph O., "Migration Patterns of Puerto Ricans", undated (Box 12, Folder 482)
    - Prewitt, Joseph O., "Insight into the Puerto Rican", undated (Box 12, Folder 483)
    - Revista (review of Puerto Rican prose and poetry), 1977 (Box 12, Folder 484)
    - In US, newspaper clippings, 1977, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 485)
    - Address by the Governor of Puerto Rico, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 486)
    - Lopez-Yustos, R.A., The Puerto Ricans: A People that refuses to Die", undated (Box 12, Folder 487)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 488)
    - Perez, Jose G., "Puerto Rico: U.S. Colony in the Caribbean", 1976 (Box 12, Folder 489)
    - Prewitt, Joseph O., "Intragroup Difference in Case of Puerto Rico", undated (Box 12, Folder 490)
    - "The Puerto Rican Experience"; bibliography, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 491)
    - "Puerto Rico", undated (Box 12, Folder 492)
    - "Puerto Rico and Puerto Ricans," (educational packet), undated (Box 12, Folder 493)
    - Riestra, Miguel A., "Puerto Rico: Historical and Socio- Cultural Foundations for a Philosophy of Education", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 494)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, "Images of Puerto Rico", undated (Box 12, Folder 495)
  - Romanians
    - Asken, Saul, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 496)
    - Bordeianu, Ovidui, Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 497)
  - Russians
    - Kubeck, Mary Jane, "Russian Orthodoxy in Meriden", undated (Box 12, Folder 498)
    - S.S. Peter and Paul Russian Orthodox Church (Calender), 1974 (Box 12, Folder 499)
    - Alpert, Yetta, Oral history summary, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 500)
    - McKain, Walter C., "Na Obshchestvennikh Nachalakh", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 501)
  - Scots and Scotch-Irish
    - Round Hill Highland Scottish Games (Stamford), 1975 (Box 12, Envelope 502)
    - Campbell, Rev. David, Oral history summary, undated (Box 12, Folder 503)
    - Field, Margaret, Oral history summary, undated (Box 12, Folder 504)
    - McConnell, Elaine, Oral history summary, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 505)
    - MacLeod, John, Oral history summary, undated (Box 12, Folder 506)
    - MacRae, John, Oral history summary, undated (Box 12, Folder 507)
    - Peebles, Charles, Oral history summary, undated (Box 12, Folder 508)
    - In CT; biographies, undated (Box 12, Folder 509)
    - "Gathering of the Scottish Clans" (New Hampshire), 1978 (Box 12, Folder 510)
    - Piotrowski, Thaddeus M., The Scots and their Descendents in the Manchester, N.H. Area, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 511)
    - Berthoff, Roland, Scots in North America; bibliography, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 512)
    - Calling All Scots, 1974-1978 (Box 12, Folder 513)
    - The Highlander, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 514-519)
    - Newsletter, Scottish American Heritage, Inc., 1976 (Box 13, Folder 520)
    - Parker, Donald Dean, "Scottish and Scotch-Irish Ancestry Research", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 521)
    - The Scotia News, 1974-1980 (Box 13:522-527, Folder 522-527)
    - "Scottish Crafts come to America", undated (Box 13, Folder 528)
    - Scotland in general; newspaper clipping, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 529)
  - Shakers
    - Brainard, Jessie M., "Mother's Ann's Children in CT: The Enfield Shakers", 1897 (Box 13, Folder 530)
    - William Benton Museum (Storrs), Broadsheet, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 531)
    - Newspaper clipping (New Hampshire), 1977 (Box 13, Folder 532)
    - The Shaker Museum (New York), undated (Box 13, Folder 533)
    - Elam, Aida and Miriam Wall, "History of the Shakers", undated (Box 13, Folder 534)
    - Taylor, Frank G., "An Analysis of the Development of Shaker Education", 1974 (Box 13, Envelope 535)
    - Williams, John S., "The Shakers", 1972 (Box 13, Folder 536)
    - The World of Shaker, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 537)
  - Slovenians
    - In general, undated (Box 13, Folder 538)
  - Spaniards
    - Ortega, Noel, Spaniards in North America; bibliography, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 539)
    - Student paper, undated (Box 13, Folder 540)
  - Swedes
    - Emanuel Lutheran Church (Hartford), undated (Box 13, Folder 541)
    - Zion Lutheran Church (Portland), 1974 (Box 13, Folder 542)
    - American Swedish Historical Foundation (newsletter), 1974 (Box 13, Folder 543)
    - History of Augustana College, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 544)
    - Maps of Swedish and Norwegian born population of US in 1880, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 545)
    - Minnesskrift, 1889-1914 (Hartford) (Box 13, Folder 546)
    - Nothstein, Ira Oliver, The Planting of the Swedish Church in America, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 547)
    - Schersten, Albert Ferdinand, Schersten, Albert Ferdinand, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 548)
    - Swanson, Alan, Swedes in North America; bibliography, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 549)
    - Visit of Carl XVI Gustaf (King), 1976 (Box 13, Folder 550)
  - Swiss
    - Fluckiger, Cheryl A., "The Apostolic Christian Church of Ellington, CT", undated (Box 13, Folder 551)
    - Schelbert, Leo, Swiss in North America; bibliography, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 552)
    - Albert Schweitzer, undated (Box 13, Folder 553)
  - Turks
    - PTAA News, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 554-555)
    - Turkey Today, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 556)
    - United Turkish American, Newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 557)
    - United Turkish American, Newsletter, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 558)
    - Christmas, newspaper clipping, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 559)
    - Turk Birligi, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 560)
  - Ukrainians
    - Colman, Lee, "Individualization in Ukrainian Classes", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 561)
    - Procko, Bohdan P., Ukrainians in North America; bibliography, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 562)
    - (In Canada) Colman, Lee, "Education of the Culturally Divergent", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 563)
  - Venezuelan
    - Nieto, Jose, Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 564)
  - Welsh
    - Ellis, David M., Welsh in North America; bibliography, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 565)
  - West Indian
    - Comrie, Elvis A., Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 566)
    - Georges, Lila, Oral history, undated (Box 13, Folder 567)
    - Martin, Austin N.W., Oral history transcript, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 568)
  - Multiple Ethnic Groupings
    - "Bicentennial Projects: An Inventory of Ethnic, Historical and Cultural Societies", undated (Box 13, Folder 569)
    - "Manhattan's Lower East Side", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 570)
    - "Manhattan's Lower East Side", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 571)
    - Sociology and Eastern Europe, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 572)
- Series VII: Research Materials on Ethnicity and Immigration, undated, 1936-1979
  - Ethnicity in Hartford
    - Hatch, Ronald L., "The Everywhere School," (Sand), undated (Box 14, Folder 573)
    - Mayor's All-American Festival, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 574)
    - "People of Greater Hartford" (school systems and student population), undated (Box 14, Folder 575)
    - Robertson, L.J. Jr., (WPA) Statistics, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 576)
    - Stave, Bruce, "Making Hartford Home", 1979 (Box 14, Envelope 577)
  - Ethnicity in Connecticut
    - "Attitude Toward Racial Integration in Connecticut", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 578)
    - Civil Rights Commission, undated (Box 14, Folder 579)
    - "College Admission Practices with Respect to Race, Religion and National Origin", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 580)
    - "Comparative study of Negro and White Dropouts in Selected Connecticut High Schools", 1959 (Box 14, Folder 581)
    - Connecticut Demography, undated (Box 14, Folder 582)
    - Ethnic Christmas Customs, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 583)
    - Federal Writers Project, Index to Materials on files in Dwight Street Office, undated (Box 14, Folder 584)
    - Hadden, Kenneth, "Nativity and Racial Composition", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 585)
    - Maps, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 586)